The music lover. He had a love of life. But was torn by it. He reached out for the
sensual. And was burned by it. His genius demanded a price. And he paid it.
The Music Lovers is a drama, music film directed by Ken Russell.
Composer, conductor and teacher Peter Ilych Tchaikovsky struggles against his homosexual tendencies by
marrying, but unfortunately, he chooses wacky nymphomaniac Nina, whom he is unable to satisfy.
Pyotr Ilyich Tchaikovsky, played by Richard Chamberlain.
Antonina 'Nina' Milyukova, played by Glenda Jackson.
Nicholas Rubinstein, played by Max Adrian.
Count Anton Chiluvsky, played by Christopher Gable.
Modeste Tchaikovsky, played by Kenneth Colley.
Madame Nadedja von Meck, played by Izabella Telezynska.
The Music Lovers is a 1971 British drama film directed by Ken Russell
and starring Richard Chamberlain and Glenda Jackson.
The screenplay by Melvyn Bragg, based on Beloved Friend, a collection of personal correspondence edited by Catherine Drinker Bowen
and Barbara von Meck, focuses on the life and career of 19th-century Russian composer Pyotr Ilyich Tchaikovsky.
It was one of the director's biographical films about classical composers, which include Elgar (1962), Delius: Song
of Summer (1968), Mahler (1974) and Lisztomania (1975), made from an often idiosyncratic standpoint.
The film explores themes of composer, biography, historical
figure, male homosexuality, 19th century.
The tone is emotional.